<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:atom='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'>
<channel>
<atom:link href='TODO' rel='self' type='application/rss+xml'/>
<title>
the scratch castle
</title>
<link>
TODO
</link>
<description>
TODO
</description>
<lastBuildDate>
Thu, 18 Feb 2016 17:44:14 -0800
</lastBuildDate>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<item>
<guid>
TODO/posts/emacs-and-helm.html
</guid>
<link>
TODO/posts/emacs-and-helm.html
</link>
<title>
Why I Use Helm and Why You Should Too
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Emacs is a whirlwind of shortcuts and commands for a beginner. Because Emacs isn't a true modal editor like VIM you must learn a plethora of keyboard shortcuts to edit text efficiently.  Richard Stallman, the creator of GNU Emacs was well aware of this so he created the &quot;GNU Emacs Human Interface Machine&quot;, which was a specially designed keyboard for Emacs power users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Picture below is an example of one of these machines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/emacs-human-interface-machine.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/img&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt; The GNU Emacs Human Interface Machine &lt;figcaption&gt; They keyboard impressed its users so much that they often felt compelled to put on a suit before operating it! &lt;/figcaption&gt; &lt;/figcaption&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All joking aside, Emacs's default interface isn't very user friendly when you don't know the shortcut or command name.  When you run a command that requires user input, you're given an empty prompt. That's it.  If you read the tutorial then you may remember that you can press TAB to see some options. That's a little better I suppose, but it would be better if you could see your possibilities without asking for it.  Enter helm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/emacs-helm/helm'&gt;Helm&lt;/a&gt; is an extension package for Emacs that, among other things, hooks into many of the commands requiring user input and supplants them with a new command that presents the user with a prompt AND an interactive list of options that is fuzzy matched to what is typed in that prompt. It's sort of similar to the &lt;a href='http://docs.sublimetext.info/en/latest/file_management/file_management.html'&gt;goto anything&lt;/a&gt; commands that are available in Sublime Text except it's available  on more than just a handful of commands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Say I want to find a window command that splits the window into two vertical halves and all I know is that the command has 'window' and 'split' in its name and I'm not sure which term is first.  Helm makes it extremely easy to browse the available symbols(names) in the current Emacs environment using the 'helm-apropos' command.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/helm-apropos.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the demo above, I run 'helm-apropos' and try searching for a command that has 'window' followed by 'split' in its name.  I find nothing appropriate so I try the reverse and search for a command with 'split' followed by 'window in its name.  I eventually find the correct answer which is 'split-window-right'.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's an important feature to note about this kind of UI that isnt immediately obvious.  Because you're presented with all the possibilities, you end up learning the capabilities of the program by simply using the program.  Because of this side effect, Emacs became a much more understandable system after I installed helm. It's such a boon to the Emacs experience that I would consider changing editors if helm wasn't available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Below I outline some useful helm commands followed by my favorite helm extension packages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;built-in&amp;#95;helm&amp;#95;commands&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Built-In Helm Commands&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;helm-find-file&amp;#95;/&amp;#95;bound&amp;#95;to&amp;#95;c-x&amp;#95;c-f&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;helm-find-file / Bound to C-x C-f&lt;/h3&gt;Use this command to navigate your file system and open files.  The 'helm-find-file' command presents you with a list of files in your current working directory.  Pressing C-l will move you up to the parent's directory.  If your cursor is on a directory, C-j will move you into it.  Press RETURN to open a file.  Easy peasy.&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/helm-find-file.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Demo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;helm-m-x&amp;#95;/&amp;#95;bound&amp;#95;to&amp;#95;c-m&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;helm-M-x / Bound to C-m&lt;/h3&gt;This command is similar to 'helm-apropos' except you're only presented with commands and pressing RETURN on a command will execute that command.&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/helm-M-x.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Demo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use helm-M-x as an alternative to typing M-x.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;helm-google&amp;#95;/&amp;#95;no&amp;#95;default&amp;#95;binding&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;helm-google / No default binding&lt;/h3&gt;Search Google with helm.  The nice thing about this command is that results are populated as you type, just like searching Google in a browser.  Press return on a result to open the link in your default browser.&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/helm-google.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Demo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;helm-apropos&amp;#95;/&amp;#95;bound&amp;#95;to&amp;#95;c-x&amp;#95;c&amp;#95;a&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;helm-apropos / Bound to C-x c a&lt;/h3&gt;helm-apropos shows you the symbols(or name) of every possible command, function, variable, and face that is available in Emacs.  Think of it as a list of everything you can do and everything that is defined in Emacs.  Press enter on a command to see the help associated with it.&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;An important thing to note about this command is that the list of symbols may change throughout the Emacs process's lifetime.  That's because Emacs is, for lack of a better term, clay.  You may not be aware of this but Emacs is a living, breathing Lisp environment.  You can change the meaning of defined symbols on-the-fly or add new definitions without having to restart Emacs.  This is the magic behind those demos you might have seen of programming in a &lt;a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7XUWpze_A_s'&gt;live lisp environment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;helm&amp;#95;extensions&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Helm Extensions&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;helm-dash&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;helm-dash&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The helm-dash package lets you search programming language  documentation through &quot;docsets&quot; you've installed on your machine.  Install docsets for a language using the 'helm-dash-install-docset'  command and search them using the 'helm-dash' command.  Press RETURN  on a result to open the documentation in your default browser.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/areina/helm-dash'&gt;helm-dash github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;evalator&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;evalator&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evalator is a new kind of REPL that I wrote for Emacs that lets  you interactively transform data. It evaluates expressions in   Emacs Lisp by default but it can support any language provided  you've installed the evaluation context package.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use evalator mainly as a calculator and a quick experimentation tool  when I'm writing Emacs Lisp and Clojure code.  It feels much quicker  than using a normal REPL because expressions are evaluated  automatically.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evalator starts with a prompt where you supply an expression to  generate the initial data.  Following expressions transform that data  on a per-element basis its makes it very easy to transform lists and other  collections.  You can also use evalator in explicit mode, which allows  you to transform data as usual, but it lets you generate the  equivalent code of the entire transformation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/seanirby/evalator'&gt;evalator github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;helm-descbinds&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;helm-descbinds&lt;/h2&gt;I really love this one.  helm-descbinds shows you all the shortcuts  that can be executed based on your current major-mode and minor modes.&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/emacs-helm/helm-descbinds'&gt;helm-descbinds github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;helm-projectile&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;helm-projectile&lt;/h2&gt;If you've ever wanted to browse all the files in a particular directory ala Sublime Text then you want helm-projectile.&lt;p&gt;helm-projectile is a helm extension for the projectile package, which  provides utilities for managing your programming projects.  A project  is essentially a folder with files.  Projects are automatically added  to projectile if they have a VCS directory like a '.git' or '.svn'.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are tons of useful projectile commands I could demo, but  &lt;a href='http://tuhdo.github.io/helm-projectile.html'&gt;tuhdo covered this better than I ever could&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://tuhdo.github.io/helm-projectile.html'&gt;helm-projectile github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope by now that I've convinced you to check out helm.  It really  is an innovative way of interacting with Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;— sean&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Thu, 18 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
TODO/posts/a-simple-keyboard-macro-demo.html
</guid>
<link>
TODO/posts/a-simple-keyboard-macro-demo.html
</link>
<title>
A Simple Keyboard Macro Demo
</title>
<description>
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe id=&quot;embedded&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/K0Rw08es0Hs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Thu, 11 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
TODO/posts/parsing-an-elisp-file-with-evalator.html
</guid>
<link>
TODO/posts/parsing-an-elisp-file-with-evalator.html
</link>
<title>
Parsing an Elisp File with Evalator
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Last month I released my first Emacs package, &lt;a href='https://github.com/seanirby/evalator'&gt;evalator&lt;/a&gt;.  It's basically a new kind of REPL for transforming data.  It can support multiple languages such as &lt;a href='https://github.com/seanirby/evalator-clojure'&gt;Clojure&lt;/a&gt; and it also provides some cool features like history and code generation.  I knew it would be a useful tool because I was using it to help me build it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While can certainly start using evalator now, it's kind of in an experimental stage.  Once it's a more fully formed thing I'll write an extensive post here.  For now, I want to share this video where I show how to parse an Elisp file with evalator.  This video demonstrates one of the coolest features of Lisp: &lt;a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homoiconicity'&gt;homoiconicity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe id=&quot;embedded&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OMDHmULenVU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find evalator on MELPA and MELPA stable. Install it by running:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;M-x package-install evalator &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can also install evalator-clojure which includes a clojure evaluation context:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;M-x package-install evalator-clojure &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;See the Github repos for &lt;a href='https://github.com/seanirby/evalator'&gt;evalator&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='https://github.com/seanirby/evalator'&gt;evalator-clojure&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; sean&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Tue, 09 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800
</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
